# Curriculum vitae

Name Stephen Wanyoike Kamara

Age 22

Phone no 0742739981

Address 49, 10105

Email stephenwanyoike528@gmail.com

#### Vision

As an IT student my career interest leans more toward **web application design and networking**. I feel comfortable with networking tasks more than web application development though am quite good at both. I hope to gain industrial experience and get used to working under strict industrial timelines and pressure.

#### Education

Year	Institution	Deliverable
2021 - 2024	Dedan Kimathi university of Technology	Degree (undergraduate)
2015 - 2018	Baricho Boys high school	KCSE (B+)
2004 - 2014	Kambi Primary School	KCPE (393)

## **Skills**

- ❖ I possess considerable prowess in **networking** having completed my networking undergraduate course plus a considerable time spent working with cisco packet tracer.
- **❖** Web application design.
- ❖ I am enrolled in the cisco CCNA with David Bombal as my mentor.
- I also possess cybersecurity skills especially pentesting having completed my certification in introduction to cybersecurity and the famous cisco begginer's course linux fundamentals.
- ❖ I am a member of the hackthebox academy community with Networkchuck as my mentor.
- Teamwork.
- Teaching and training.
- Self-drive (minimum supervision)

#### Work experience

Year Institute Position
-------------------------

Jan 2020 – September 2020	Naromoru victory academy	Teacher (English, Kiswahili and
		basic computer )
April 2019 – July 2019	Mt. Kenya Naromoru computer	Instructor on basic computer
	training institute	packages

#### **Projects**

- 1. **Windows port scan** project requirement for internal attachment end of year 2. I had been having trouble with my windows security and needed a quick way on how to automate the closing and opening of udp and tcp ports whenever i wanted.
- 2. **Simple ice cream order app** project requirement for 3<sup>rd</sup> year android development. The app is limited to payment by m-pesa only though with a few upgrades, i can integrate credit card payment. Will upload it to github account upon completion.

# **Certifications**

- 1. Introduction to cybersecurity
- 2. Ccna1
- 3. Ccna2
- 4. Ccna3

Currently working on a project – tomato leaf disease detection using machine learning.

### References

- Mr. Grieves Gachari
   HoD geography department Naromoru victory academy 0726405312
- Amos Karofia
   Manager equity bank Mwea branch
   0722604882
- Mr. Maina Mbuki
   Network and systems admin
   Lecturer Dedan Kimathi University of Technology
   07218648813